<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>DORA JAMBOR</title>
    <link>https://dorajam.github.io/thoughts/</link>
    <description>Recent content on DORA JAMBOR</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 20 Sep 2016 21:53:36 +0200</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://dorajam.github.io/thoughts/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>Change of basis in a vector space</title>
      <link>https://dorajam.github.io/thoughts/post/change-of-basis/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 20 Sep 2016 21:53:36 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://dorajam.github.io/thoughts/post/change-of-basis/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The ability to make comparisons between different objects requires you to have the same perception of bases along which you can define objects.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You can think of units as the words and expressions that define a language. I may say ‘apple’ in my language, which is the same object to you as what I’m referring to, provided you speak the same language. But if you do not speak the same language, you may think of something else by the word ‘apple’. Let me get a little philosophical here. This also holds for human perception. Whatever I see is conditioned by my background, my unique past filled with my own experiences. My behaviour is then conditioned by my perception, which you will translate through your own perception. So you may wonder how we can even communicate with each other if our surroundings are understood through totally different lenses. Well.. good question!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’d love to keep going, but I’ll be nice and respect the title of this post.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To represent different points in space you need some sort of unit of measurement that allows you to speak about things in the same language. Space has no intrinsic grid. The language we choose to define space are the units by which it can broken into gridlines. The conventional way of representing points in 2D space is to use the standard coordinate system, defined by the basis vectors i and j. However, it is important to acknowledge that such basis vectors were a choice we made. We could have represented the same points by a different set of units.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So a few things you may wonder about:
(i) How to translate some point defined in one system to another?
(ii) How to understand the same linear transformation in another system?&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>